Mark Jones O. Solano

Philippines, Digos City, Davao del Sur

Mobile: +639369067328

Email: mjsolano12345@gmail.com

Website: https://mjsolano.me Github Linkln

SUMMARY

I'm a software developer from the Philippines and part of a team based in Belfast. I've been in the industry for a while now and I have had the privilege of working with people who are experienced software engineers and collaborating with them.

Throughout my career, I've had the privilege of working at some of our local business agencies, a government school, a start-up, and a huge corporation. I'm currently focused on delivering inclusive and clean software for the company.

EXPERIENCE

Cased Dimensions / Vizwoz Software Developer July 2020 - Present

- Rewarded for fixing a lot of bugs during my first 2 months in the job
- Front-end Development with Angular and React, Nodejs, and Azure DevOps
- Implements user story or feature
- Fixing bugs and design markups and methods
- Collaborate with colleague on the project implementation and a scrum method

Dominoff (Freelance/startup)

2017-2022

Full Stack Developer

- Created a mobile app for client specifications using NativeScript.
- Heavy in Front-end using Angular but also worked in back-end using Express and Nodejs.

- Designed data using Mongodb and Nodejs for API requirements.
- Implements feature and maintain code base up to date.
- Collaborate with project partner for the implementation of system.
- Provides client support and gradually seeing client for updates and support tech.
- Integrated SMS/GSM data converter into web data

Software Development Projects

Project Smiles — 2019 - Present - https://smiles.backbone.ph

Participate in developing a web-based information system for public schools as charity (<u>psmiles.org</u> - present) two local public schools (totaling approximately 6 thousand students) are currently using the information system for report card generation and statistics. More schools are being invited every year.

(Javascript, Typescript, Angular, MongoDb, Node.js, Handsontable, JSF and other libraries)

Project Outlet - 2017 - Present (3 prototypes currently deployed)

Involve in developing a web information system called for locally financed sweepstake featuring user and SMS processing and real time processing features. This is sold to prospective clients as a one-time-purchase product. There are approximately 300 users with 3.5k data processed every day.

(Typescript, SMS Relay, Angular, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Angular Material, Bootstrap, JsPdf and libraries)

• UBI media network — 2019 https://trustgraph.org – (Not Available)

Build a Universal Basic Income network whose target is a huge number of people giving them a token that can be converted to currency. Every Logged-in by a client token is automatically generated. Comes from the name itself trusting, and also a token is rewarded to the client that has the highest trust rate.

(Javascript, Typescript, Angular, MongoDb, Node.js, Angular-Apex, Facebook API, Twitter API, Google API, Linkin API and other libraries)

Other projects I'm involved with or collaborated with.

• July 2022 – Portfolio – https://mjsolano.me

My personal site created from scratch, a complete summary of my work, experience, and qualifications.

Department of Agriculture (DA) – 2021 – https://da.backbone.ph

Participate in developing a soil tracing and mapping tracing web app specially conducted integrating soil map tracing. (Javascript, Angular, MongoDb, Node.js, openstreetmap and other libraries)

• September 2019 - https://mjsol12.github.io/react-todo-list

Develop a web-based application using React front-end with basic functionalities create, delete, and marks a list of to-dos with basic routing for react showing the list and about of the application.

May 2019 - https://bitbucket.org/mjs12/bt-thermal-printer/src/master/

Develop a web-based system using MEAN stack and it was used by Junior High School last September 2019 with a real-time scoring system for judges and participants. Using Handsontable for excel like client from judges score panel to displaying calculated summary. The score was calculated through ranking based on judges highest score panel from 16 candidates down to 8 candidates for the final competition.

May 2018 - https://bitbucket.org/mjs12/bt-thermal-printer/src/master/

Develop NativeScript using Angular environment and deployed to Android Application is a system that retrieves the param data from base URI of Sweepstake web system which features printing thermal receipt in real time calculation.

• January 2018

Develop a web system that reads, data analysis and chart the external file logs came from a school internet route. Using Chart.js it displays data acquired from external files that have a prefix CSV file and data analysis defining which IP address is commonly used by the people connecting the network, especially students.

July 2017 – MEAN Stack course

CRUD Operation Mean Stack (Udemy Course) a long hour of in-depth tutorial for MEAN stack which CRUD stands As Create, Read, Update and Delete following the basic to advance programming principles that practice my skills and confidence in coding.

Stacks I'm currently involved with

Angular (v2 - v11+) Bootstrap

ReactJS Material Design

Nodejs Angular Material

ExpressJS Azure Devops

MongoDb Git

SAAS/ Custom application 3rd Party Libraries

Html and its semantics markup Other Library

CSS preprocessor like SSAS/SCSS

EDUCATION

Polytechnic College of Davao del Sur – BS Criminology (2012–2016)